

PROFILE

I am a human, husband and father, who creates, designs, teaches and occasionally writes. I was born in the suburbs of Chicago, Illinois, but have been living in the southcentral part of Chile for close to a decade.

I am looking for a challenging and meaningful employment opportunity where I can use my design, language and pedagogical skills to contribute to wonderful, meaningful projects.

EDUCATION

2007-2008

TEACHER CERT. K-12, SPANISH

Eastern Illinois University, USA

1995-2003

B.A. FOREIGN LANGUAGES (SPANISH)

Eastern Illinois University, USA

1995-2003

B.A. HISTORY, MINOR IN LATIN AMERICAN STUDIES

Fastern Illinois University USA

SKILLS

- ✓ Bilingual (English / Spanish)
- ✓ HTML / CSS / JavaScript
- ✓ PHP
- ✓ WordPress
- ✓ Photography
- ✓ Copy Editing

MIKE WALSH

DESIGNER / PROFESSOR / WRITER

Address: Casilla 134 / Villarrica / CHILE

Phone: +56 9 99373763

Email: iam@elmikewalsh.com

Website: www.elmikewalsh.com // www.imaginalgo.com

EXPERIENCE

ENGLISH PROFESSOR ECLASS | MARCH, 2015 - PRESENT

I execute online, one-on-one English classes of all levels, from the very first steps in English to the most advanced offerings the company provided. I perform my job very well and am considered highly reliable by my coordinators.

DIGITAL PRODUCT & EXPERIENCE DESIGNER IMAGINALGO | JUNE, 2007 – PRESENT

I make websites and do print designs for books/e-books, business cards, invitations, etc. My principal focus is on clean, fast, organized web coding and design which will remain relevant and modern despite changes in design trends.

PROGRAM COORDINATOR
TEACHINGCHILE | MARCH, 2012 - PRESENT

Program Coordinator. Empowered with the design, development, expansion and maintenance tasks of the website, publicity and digital presence of TeachingChile.

ENGLISH PROFESSOR

WALL ST. ENGLISH, VALDIVIA, CHILE | SEPTEMBER, 2010 - MARCH 2012

I was responsible for the execution of all levels of English classes, ranging from 1-4 students. Also carried out conversation and language reinforcement classes.

SPANISH TEACHER

TEUTOPOLIS HIGH SCHOOL, TEUTOPOLIS, IL, USA | AUGUST, 2007 - JUNE 2008

Designed, developed and utilized material for first- and second-year Spanish classes to create a dynamic and multidisciplinary presentation of the Spanish language and culture.

HOBBIES & INTERESTS

Design / Writing / Photography / Sports